

Lidya Christina Product & User Researcher

+6285691303074 id.lidya@gmail.com Jakarta.Indonesia

SUMMARY

I am Lidya based in Jakarta, Indonesia. For the past 1+ years been handled UX research projects including user interviews, quantitative & qualitative research, and usability testing. I have 4+ years of solid experience in product development with proactive evangelism for open source projects.

I enjoy sharing and collaborating, but I also accountable to deliver individual tasks. I always keen to exploring more opportunities and grow myself into new things, let's connect!

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Tester 01/2018 - Present

UTest

Manual tester for web and mobile applications and excel in translation/localization for Indonesian - English, gain a proven badge by UTest.

Familiar with management (database, method, customer support, communication, etc) and manual testing tools like Trello, basic SQL, Charles (API), Agile methodologies, Metabase, Salesforce, Zendesk, Jira, Slack, Discourse, -- keen to learn new tools/technology.

User Experience Researcher 03/2022 - 08/2022

SHAREIT

Improve the usability testing focus plan and execution for Indonesia and Bangladesh markets with above 80% delivered key insights to be implemented/improved by the product and dev team

Create database structure and effective incentive scheme for respondents which improve efficiency and the time taken to execute these administration tasks by 5-8 minutes of total +/- 15 minutes

Provide central manual SOP for the research activities of the offline and online research

User Experience Research Consultant

04/2021 - 12/2021

Migo

Successfully executed and delivered five main research plans such as parental control research, redefining personas of their users, usability testing of new features, churn user analysis, and on-demand movie research which was used mostly as the main consideration by the product, marketing, and content team.

Process Improvement Specialist

10/2018 - 01/2019

Gojek

Assist the floor management in terms of tools and the current process in customer care unit

Initiate improvement in the automation process (flow and tools)

Create an initial requirement document to deliver to the operational tech team

Communicate the flow and deliverables to tech team

Daily floor monitoring to find out the root cause of high priority issues

Assistant Product Manager

Wobe Pte. Ltd

[Assistant Product Manager (Apr 2017 - May 2018)]

Act as a liaison between engineering team and Indonesian suppliers, following up on new requests, checking error and questions, included non-business matters relation suppliers relationship

File bugs and gather insight from field reports, prioritise and manage their fixes

Taking daily scrum call and collaborate with engineering and CTO

Hired a community manager and work together to convey feedback then list it to buglists or next features

[Community Manager (Jan 2017 - Mar 2017)]

Ensuring active and engaged communities get best services and smooth journey using the app

Initiate and lead offline event

Monitoring and handle> 80% online conversation and participation to build brand and technical issues

[Management Trainee - Associate (Nov 2014 - Dec 2016)]

EDUCATION

Economy - Accounting Education

2013

11/2014 - 08/2018

Universitas Negeri Jakarta - Bachelor of Education

GPA 3.52/4.00

SKILLS

Product Management	Advanced	Product Advocate	Intermediate
User Experience Research	Expert	Cloud Technology	Beginner
Manual Testing	Advanced		

LANGUAGES

Bahasa Indonesia	Native	English	Fluent
------------------	--------	---------	--------